（ナレーション）
使い捨てられた人工衛星
Abandoned artificial satellites.
Tanks jettisoned from shuttles.
シャトルが切り離したタンク
Refuse generated during
space station construction.
ステーション建造時に出た廃棄物
This vast amount of junk floating in space,
space debris, is a very serious threat.
宇宙に浮かぶ たくさんのゴミ
スペースデブリは
実は とても危険な存在です
This is a story of 2076, a time in which
this space garbage has become a problem.
2076年―
これは 宇宙のゴミが
問題になった時代の物語
♪～
Soshite hito wa toki wo koeta yume wo miru
And people dream dreams that transcend time.
♪そして人は時空(とき)を
越えた夢を見る
seijyaku no umi ni idakarete
Held in the depths of the sea.
tori ya kumo wo miagete wa
As they look up at the stars and clouds.
♪鳥や雲を見上げては
hakanai inochi moyashita ikusen no asa ni
It set their ephemeral souls on fire on a thousand mornings.
♪儚(はかな)い生命(いのち)燃やした
♪幾千の朝に
hikari ga mukau basho he habataku darou
I bet they're taking right to where the light is headed.
♪光が向かう場所へ
♪羽ばたくだろう
daichi wo ima tori yoku kette
Now kickoff from the ground like a bird.
♪願いを放つ時は今
hatenaki yume wo noseta furontia he
Off into the frontier that is carrying boundless dreams.
♪果てなき夢を乗せた
♪フロンティアへ
tooku tooku dive in the sky
Farther and farther dive in the sky.
♪遠く遠く Dive in the Sky
Phase 15
In Her Case...
Medical checkups are only worthwhile when...
（ラビィ）
健康診断ってのはな―
毎年きちんと受けてこそ
価値があるんだよ
...you get one every year like clockwork.
Enough, already! I came here
this year, didn't I?
（ハチマキ）
いいじゃねえか―
今年は来たんだから
（フィー）
どういう心境の変化？
Why the sudden
change of heart?
入社以来 ずっと来なかったのに
You haven't come for a checkup since
the one you had when you were hired.
（ハチマキ）えっ そりゃあ…
Um...
Because an astronaut has to
take good care of himself!
（タナベ）宇宙飛行士にとって
健康は大事ですから
Right, Senpai?
ねっ 先輩
Yeah. Right.
お… おう
Right! A person's most precious
posession is his health!
（課長）
そうそう 人間健康が一番だよ
Let's all get our checkups together
every year from now on, okay?
これからも
毎年 全員で受けようね
All of us, huh?
全員ねえ
Edel-san isn't here, though...
でも エーデルさんがいませんけど
Oh, that's because she's
a contract worker.
（課長）
あっ エーちゃんは 契約社員だから
（ラビィ）そう 会社で健康診断を
受けられるのは 正社員だけ
Right, only regular employees get medical checkups.
Oh, okay.
（タナベ）そうか あの几帳面な
エーデルさんが―
I thought it was strange that someone
as punctual as Edel-san would play hooky.
サボりなんて
おかしいと思いました
I've never seen her
show up late for work.
（ハチマキ）あいつが遅刻すんの
見たことねえしな
She's never late submitting
her paperwork, either.
（ユーリ）
提出物も遅らせたことない
That girl really has
her act together.
（課長）
きっちりしてるよね 彼女
Don't you think she's a bit too tightly wound?
She could stand to loosen up a little.
けど
きっちりしすぎじゃないですか？
もう少し潤いってもんが
Yeah, I've never seen
her smile, either.
ニコリともしねえもんな
Now that you mention it,
it's hard to imagine Edel-san laughing.
そういえば エーデルさんが
笑ったとこって想像できませんね
You're the members of Debris Section, correct?
（エーデル）
デブリ課の方ですね
へっ？
（エーデル）受付のほうへどうぞ
Please follow me
to the reception desk.
（ラビィ）あれ？
What the...?
What are you doing, E-chan?
（課長）
何やってんの？ エーちゃん
There will be six
of you, then?
（エーデル）６名でよろしいですね
あの… どうして
Um, what are you...
I work here part-time
twice a month.
（エーデル）月に２回だけ
ここでアルバイトをしてるんです
それより 早く受け付けを
済ませていただけませんか？
Anyway, could we please get you
checked in as quickly as possible?
次のバイトが入っていますので
I have another job
after this.
えっ 他にもやってるんですか？
なんで そんなに…
You have another job besides this one?
Why do you have so many?
It doesn't conflict with my
contracted work hours at Technora.
今は テクノーラとの
契約時間ではありません
This way, please.
では こちらにどうぞ
はあ…
The deal will be made here at Seven.
This trio came up here yesterday.
（ギガルト）
取り引き場所は このセブンだ
昨日 ３人組が上がってきている
Geez, these guys keep coming up
here into space to make their deals.
（隊員）
たく… 次から次へと宇宙に来て
Seven is under INTO law, so even if they get
caught, the punishment will be less severe.
（ハキム）
連合法が適用されるセブンじゃ―
捕らえても刑が軽いからな
Hakim, it's not our place to decide what their punishment will be.
（ギガルト）
ハキム どんな刑を与えるかは
俺たちの仕事じゃない
Yes, sir.
（ハキム）はい
We'll arrest them while they're
making the deal. That is our...
取り引き場所を押さえるぞ
それが俺たちの… んがっ
（ハキム）せ… 先生！
（ギガルト）ううっ うっ…
Sensei?
（ハキム）ギガルト先生！
（ギガルト）ぐぐぐ…
Gigalt Sensei!
救安を呼べ！ 早く！
Call a medical team!
Hurry!
Yes, sir!
（隊員）はい おやじさん！
Old man!
くううっ…
Earrings!
（タナベ）
ピアス… は似合わないかな
Might not look good
on me...
Still, it's our first date,
so why not?
でも せっかくのデートだしな
Yuri-san, how much longer are you
going to look after this sea cucumber?
（エーデル）ユーリさん ナマコは
いつまで預かるのですか？
ああ それ
第３事業部からの頂き物だから
Oh, that was a gift
from Third Division.
（タナベ）あっ すいません
私がペットとして飼いますから
Oh, I'm sorry,
I'm going to keep it as a pet.
An animal like this?
（エーデル）この生き物をですか？
Right.
（タナベ）はい
Oh, I see.
（エーデル）そうですか
In that case, please file a personal
effects registration form.
では 私物登録の
届け出をお願いします
Okay.
（タナベ）はーい
うん たまにはピアスとかも
Maybe it'd be nice to wear
earrings for a change...
Those are for Lingum piercings.
（エーデル）それ リンガムですよ
（タナベ）え？
えっ リンガムって？
Lingum? What's that?
It's a tongue piercing.
They go through the underside of the tongue.
舌にするピアス
舌の裏側に
えぐるように通すんです
ええっ そうなの
Really?
ええ？
I don't think they would
look good on you.
似合わないと思いますよ
（タナベ）えっ？
ピアス
Earrings.
You don't?
そうですか？
ええ 似合わないと思います
あなたには
No, I don't.
They wouldn't suit you at all.
（タナベ）んんん…
Hey, which do you think
would look better?
（ハチマキ）
なあなあ どっちがいいと思う？
（トモルド）右かな
The right one, I guess.
But if you wear that, you'll want something
on your neck. Like a choker or something.
でも それだったら
首にポイントが欲しいな
チョーカーとか
I don't have
a damn choker.
そんなの持ってねえよ
お前 貸してくれよ
Let me borrow one!
俺も持ってないって
I don't have one, either.
おっ おーい チェンシン
Hey! Cheng-Shin!
（チェンシン）ん？ 何か用かい？
Need something?
You have a choker, right? Let Hachi borrow it.
お前さ チョーカー持ってたよな
（ハチマキ）ああっ
ハチに貸してやってくんねえか
- T-That's okay!
いいんだよ そんなの
おっ 何 持ってんだよ チェンシン
What's that you
have there, Cheng-Shin?
Oh, that's the pamphlet
for the Jupiter project.
（チェンシン）
ああ 木星計画のパンフレット
I hear they're going to put out a call for Von Braun crew applicants inside the company.
フォン･ブラウン号の乗組員
社内公募するらしいから
You're gonna apply?
申し込むのか？
Yes, but the competition is probably going to be tough.
（チェンシン）
競争率は高いだろうけどね
How about you, Hachi? It sounds exciting.
ハチはどうする？ 面白そうだよ
俺か？ 俺は…
Who, me?
Well, I...
ああっ… 無理 無理
Nah, it's hopeless! They're just gonna pick
people from Control and Astrogation, right?
どうせ
管制課か航宙課で決まりだろ？
They'll show me the door once
they hear I'm from Half Section.
半課じゃ 門前払いさ
Hey, that's right! You always talked about wanting to be the captain of the Von Braun, didn't ya?
そっかあ フォン･ブラウンの
船長になりたいって―
前から言ってたもんな
Give 'em hell, Cheng-Shin!
頑張れよ チェンシン
（チェンシン）ああ？
あっ タナベ君？
Who, Tanabe-kun?
She's taking a personal
day today.
（ラビィ）今日は有休を取ってるよ
Today is the deadline for her to renew her EVA license.
船外作業免許の更新
今日が締め切りなんですが
And I don't think she's handed in her registration for the sea cucumber yet, either.
ナマコの私物登録も
まだみたいですし
Being one day late
is no big deal.
まあ いいじゃない
１日くらい遅れたって
If a temp worker like me put off doing
her job, I'd be in breach of contract!
派遣の私が仕事を遅らせたら
契約違反になるんです
Please don't assume that I'm like an official
employee like you are, Assistant Manager.
社員の係長補佐と
一緒にしないでください
Hey, I have a lot
going on right now.
私だって いろいろあるんだよ
And anyway, I'm your superior.
No, you could even say I'm your employer.
大体 僕は君の上司
いや 雇い主とも言えるんだよ
But forget about that.
This thing is harder than it looks.
そんなことより
これ 思ったより大変でさ
何か いいコツ 知らない？
Do you know any good tips
for playing it?
ん？
Mail?
（エーデル）
メール？ このアドレス…
Wait, this address is...
Sasha?!
サーシャ
（ハチマキ）んっ…
んっ… あ…
Say something, damn it.
何か話せよ
何かって？
Like what?
Like anything.
何でもいい
Well, how long have you
had feelings for me, Senpai?
じゃあ 先輩は―
いつから
私のこと好きだったんですか？
（せき込み）
What kind of question
is that?!
聞くか そういうこと
You told me to say "anything,"
didn't you?
何でもいいって
言ったじゃないですか
How about you?
お前はどうなんだよ
Who, me?
私ですか？
I think it was...
私は…
Maybe it was when I first
went out into space with you.
私は
先輩と初めて宇宙に出たときかも
Oh. No kidding...
ああ そう
Now it's your turn, Senpai.
I told you, so now you go!
次 先輩の番ですよ
私 言ったんですから
あっ 俺は…
Well, I...
ああっ… 俺は…
I guess it was...
（チェンシン）ハチ？
（ハチマキ）あっ…
Hachi?
（タナベ）チェンシンさん
Cheng-Shin-san?!
Um, we were just... That is, we...
（ハチマキ）
ああ いや あの… これは その…
How's it look?
どうだ？
（女性隊員）２人だけ
I only see two.
この男が来ていません
This man isn't here.
He stayed in
the hotel, huh?
（ハキム）ホテルに残ったか
What should we do?
（女性隊員）どうします？
Hugo is over at the hotel. We'll stick to
the plan and stake out the restaurant.
ホテルはフムが行ってる
我々は予定どおり 店内で張るぞ
Hakim!
ハキム
（ハキム）ん？
How's Old Man Gigalt doing?
ギガルトのおやじさんは？
They took him
to the hospital.
病院に運んだ
Oh.
そう
ギガルト先生のことだ
This is Gigalt Sensei
we're talking about.
我々が
任務を終えて戻るころには… ん？
By the time we have this mission
wrapped up, he'll probably...
Hoshino?
星野(ほしの)…
（女性隊員）知り合い？
You know that man?
Yeah.
（ハキム）ああ 作戦変更だ
Okay, change in plans.
We'll let Ron's team handle the restaurant.
店内は ロンのチームに任せる
I'm a real bastard...
（ハチマキ）
その… 最低だよな 俺って
お前の気持ち 知ってたのに
I knew how you felt,
but I lied to you.
俺は うそをついてたんだ
I never meant to lie to you or
to myself about how I felt, but I...
チェンシンにも 自分の気持ちにも
うそをつくつもりは
なかったんだけど…
No, I'm just
making excuses.
From your point of view,
it's a simple case of betrayal.
その… チェンシンから見れば
ただの裏切りだし―
Go ahead and hit me or kick me. I deserve it!
殴るなり蹴るなり
お前のしたいようにしてくれ
Deep down, I guess I knew.
（チェンシン）
分かってたよ 何となく
えっ？
She'd been turning me
down lately.
最近 断られてばっかりだったし
I'm sorry.
（タナベ）すみません
Cheng-Shin, I...
（ハチマキ）チェンシン 俺…
気にするなよ ハチ
Don't worry about it, Hachi.
It's not like Tanabe-san and I were married or anything.
別に 俺とタナベさんは
結婚してたわけじゃないし―
I don't think I have a claim on her
just because we slept together once.
権利を主張しようなんて
思わないさ
一度 寝たくらいで
（ハチマキ）いっ
（タナベ）えっ？
そ… そうだよな
Y-Yeah, I guess not... It's not like we're
grade schoolers or something.
中学生とかじゃあるまいし
そのくらい…
That doesn't mean...
We did no such thing! Cheng-Shin!
（タナベ）
違いますよ！ チェンシンさん
Sorry, sorry... I'm just kidding, Hachi.
ごめん ごめん 冗談だよ ハチ
えっ
Tanabe-san and I never
even kissed.
キスもしてないよ タナベさんとは
うん
（ハチマキ）お前 性格 悪いぞ
You have a warped personality,
you know that?
（チェンシン）ささやかな復讐さ
Call it a little payback.
You can allow me that much, right?
それくらい 許されるだろ？
Good work, Dolf-kun.
（専務）ドルフ君 お疲れ
Second Division was the clear leader
again this quarter.
今期も第２事業部の
一人勝ちだねえ
Thank you, sir.
（ドルフ）ありがとうございます
What do you say? Would you care
to join me for a drink later?
（専務）どうだ？ よかったら
このあと つきあわないか？
I'm sorry, sir, but I've
already made plans.
申し訳ありません
先約がありますので
はあ… ふん
Turning down an invitation from the
Executive Vice President like that...
（ノーマン）
専務の誘いを断るなんて―
何様のつもりなんでしょうね
Who does he think
he is?
The next Executive Vice President, possibly.
未来の専務様… かもしれんな
なっ…
Assistant Chief, would you mind
if I took the afternoon off?
課長補佐 午後から
お休みを頂けませんか？
えっ？
Even contract workers are
entitled to paid time off.
（エーデル）契約社員でも
有休は認められているはずです
With the supervisor's consent,
of course.
担当者の承諾が
Sure, that's okay. We'll pretend
that you were here working.
いいよ いいよ
出勤扱いにしとくから
え？
いつも よくやってくれてるし―
You always do such great work here. Besides, everybody is taking the day off, anyway.
どうせ今日は みんな休みだしさ
You don't have to be so formal
about everything, E-chan.
エーちゃんも
そんな堅苦しく考えないでさ
Just make up the hours
by the end of the month.
月末までに
帳尻合わしてくれればいいから
Okay?
ねえ？
（エーデル）
いえ 休みは休みですから
No, sir.
Time off
is time off.
（サーシャ）ああ… ん…
Man, that Cheng-Shin sure has
a mean streak, doesn't he?
（ハチマキ）チェンシンのやつも
結構 意地が悪いよな
So, what do you
want to do now?
（タナベ）
…で これから どうしましょうか？
Um... Hachirota-san?
あの… 八郎太(はちろうた)さん
はあっ 今 何か言ったか？
お前 変なこと
Did you say something just now? Something weird?
だって いつまでも
“ハチマキ先輩”じゃ…
Well, I can't keep calling you
Hachimaki Senpai, can I?
No! Absolutely not!
Just call me Hachimaki!
駄目！ その呼び方 駄目！
“ハチマキ”でいい
But if we're going out...
でも つきあってるのに…
You call me by my name,
so I should also...
私のことも
名前で呼んでくれたって
- Tanabe?
（シャポウ）タナベ？
（タナベ）えっ へっ？
You have the
day off, too?
（ヴァンリ）タナベも休みか？
How do you do? I'm Chapeau,
I joined at the same time as Tanabe.
（シャポウ）はじめまして
タナベと同期のシャポウです
Um... I'm Hoshino. I work at
Debris Section with Tanabe-san.
あっ タナベさんと同じ
デブリ課の星野です
星野？
Hoshino?
ひょっとして おむつ男？
（ヴァンリ）あっ
Wait a minute... Diaper Man?!
ああっ ご… ごめんね
シャポウ ヴァンリ
Um, I'm sorry, Chapeau, Vanli.
We're in a bit of a hurry.
私たち 急ぐから
（ハチマキ）うあっ
Hey! Tanabe! Introduce us, darn it!
ちょっと タナベ
ちゃんと紹介しなさいよー
ハァ… なんだって
知り合いばっかなんだよ
Geez, why do we keep
running into people we know?
It can't be helped.
しかたないですよ
This promenade is the only
place on Seven where people can go for fun.
セブンで遊べる所って
この通りだけですもん
What do people usually do
at times like this?
みんな
こういうとき どうしてんだ？
How about going aboard Toy Box?
If we go there, nobody...
ToyBox(トイボックス)の中とかどうでしょう
あそこなら
That's where we work.
あそこは仕事する所だ
It wouldn't feel
much like a date there, you know?
それじゃあ
デートって気がしねえだろ？
（タナベ）フッ
Isn't there anywhere else?
どっか なかったかなあ ああ…
（リュシー）
何やってんの？ こんな所で
What are you two
doing here?
Lucie!
（タナベ）リュシー
（ハチマキ）また知り合いだよ
Here we go again...
（リュシー）バカね
You two sillies. Seven has its own little rules for dating.
セブンには セブンの
デートのしかたってものがあるのよ
Um, isn't this a...
（タナベ）あのさ ここって…
Yep. Seven's only establishment for overnight lodgings.
（リュシー）
うん セブン唯一の宿泊施設
Hotel Spica.
ホテル スピカよ
（タナベ）ホテル！？
（ハチマキ）うっ
A hotel?!
What are you
shouting for?
（リュシー）何 大声 出してんのよ
B-But it's a...
（タナベ）だ… だって
（リュシー）
やだ 別に 泊まるわけじゃないわよ
Oh, come on, it's not like you're going
to stay here overnight or anything.
You get the room for a few hours, and
you watch a movie or eat or whatever.
時間で部屋 借りて
映画 見たり 食事したりするの
There's no other way to be all by
yourselves on Seven, you know?
そうじゃないと セブンでは
２人きりになれないでしょ？
なるほど
Oh, I get it...
Everybody does it.
みんな そうしてるわ
Of course, you could always
spend the night, too.
もちろん
そのまま泊まってもいいけど？
えっ いや あの…
俺はそんなこと あ… あの
Um, I wouldn't... That is, I... Um...
Look at you, getting
all flustered!
（リュシー）
何 テレてんのよ ウフフ
（クレア）
受注経験のある企業は―
The firms that we've ordered from in the past
are on the list I gave you the other day.
先日お渡しした
リストのとおりです
This is a list of companies
that have just been added.
こちらは
新規参入企業のリストです
I guess I'll go ahead
and take it.
（男性）ああ
一応 頂いておきましょうかね
They're all companies in
developing countries, right?
どうせ
発展途上国の企業ばかりでしょ？
発注はありえませんが
We'll never place any orders with them.
（男性）では
フォン･ブラウン絡みは最優先で
Well, give top priority to any work
related to the Von Braun.
（クレア）分かりました
Understood, sir.
連合の事業は
先進国クラブで持ち回り
INTO's business only goes to
members of the First World club.
いつものことだけど
I guess that
never changes.
ハチ
Hachi?
Wow! This room
is pretty big!
（タナベ）
へえ 結構 広いんですねえ
A projection TV, too!
You can watch movies and things on this!
あっ プロジェクター
これで映画とか見るんだ
うわっ…
Wow! This potted plant is real!
- I told Tanabe how I feel, and she's okay with it...
（ハチマキ）俺はタナベに告白して
ＯＫもらったわけだし
キスもしたし 大人なんだし
And we've kissed... And we're both adults, too...
I-I guess that just about covers everything
as etiquette for this kinda thing goes...
あ… ありだよな 普通
礼儀としても
Look at this, Senpai!
It's a balloon-style rescue ball!
先輩 ほら 風船式の救命ボール
こんなに小さくて…
Look at how small it is!
うわあっ
（ハチマキ）ああっ
（タナベ）すみません 先輩
I-I'm sorry, Senpai...
はっ…
Tanabe, I...
タナベ 俺…
ああっ 先輩！
Senpai!
ああっ 悪い 俺…
I'm sorry, I didn't mean...
No, not that! There's someone here!
違うんです 誰かいます
何！？
（タナベ）ベッドの陰
What?
Behind the bed!
誰かいるのか？
いるなら出てこい！
Is anybody there?!
If you're back there, come on out!
泥棒か？ 痴漢か？
警察 呼ぶぞ！
Are you a thief? A pervert?!
I'm gonna call the cops!
W-Wait, don't!
You don't need to worry about me.
（サーシャ）ま… 待ってくれ
怪しい者じゃない
How much more suspicious can you get?!
You were hiding behind our bed!
そんな所に隠れてたくせに
何言ってんだ！
Well, I had
a good reason...
（サーシャ）
それが ちょいと訳ありで
どんな訳だよ
Yeah, like what?
話すと長くなるんだが―
Well, it's a long story.
To sum it up
in one word, it'd be "love," I guess.
ひと言で言うなら“愛”かな
Love?
愛？
はあ？
It was love at first sight. We were
drawn to each other like magnets.
（サーシャ）
俺たちは一瞬で恋に落ちて―
磁石みたいに愛し合った
I proposed to her just two weeks
after we met.
出会ってからプロポーズまで
たった２週間だったけど―
But we packed more living
into those two weeks...
腐れ役人どもの一生より
ずっと輝いた２週間だったよ
...than a lousy government official
experiences in a whole lifetime.
After I proposed, I went to ask
her parents for approval.
それから俺は 彼女の両親に
結婚を許してもらいに行った
I was even wearing a suit, which is
totally out of character for me.
柄にもなく
スーツなんか着ちゃってさ
But I was turned down.
けど追い返された
Why?
どうして？
"We can't give our daughter
to a foreigner," they said.
外国人に娘はやれないってさ
But I refused to give up,
and I went to their house again.
それでも諦めきれなくて
もう一度 家を訪ねたら―
But they had already sent her away
to a place I could never reach her.
彼女は もう俺の手の届かない所へ
移されちまってた
手の届かない所って？
Where you could never
reach her?
Into space, huh?
宇宙か？
（サーシャ）うん
セブンにいるんですか？ その人
Is she on Seven? Is that where she is?!
そういうこと
That's right. And I made arrangements
to meet her here in this room today.
それで今日 彼女と この部屋で
会うことになってるんだ
なんで この部屋なんだよ
Why this room?
I wrote down
the wrong number.
いや 書き間違えちゃって
I meant to write room 25,
but I put down 35 instead.
25号室って書くつもりが
35号室って
♪～
（殴る音）
Old man! You've got a visitor!
（社員）おっさん 客だ
Who is it?
（チャド）どなたですか？
（社員）さあ…
ローン会社のやつとかじゃないの？
Beats me. He looks like he's from
a loan company or something.
久しぶりだな
It's been
a long time.
Dolf!
ドルフ！？
We're short on flight directors over
in Second Division. How about it?
第２事業部で
フライトディレクターが足りない
どうだ？
Who, me?
俺を？
Third Division doesn't know how
to make the best use of their people.
第３事業部は
人の使い方が下手だな
You're no accountant, Chad.
チャドに経理なんて
できるわけがない
You're not cut out for it.
Thanks for the vote
of confidence.
（チャド）言ってくれるな
It's an accurate judgment.
正確な判断だ
That's one thing about you
that will never change.
変わらないな
お前のそういうところ
ほんと変わらないよ
Not in a million years.
I worked myself half to death
these past five years.
（サーシャ）
この５年 死ぬ気で頑張ってさ
And now I finally have
a restaurant of my own.
ようやく店を持てたんだ
小さいけど味は抜群
It's small, but our food
is second to none.
If you're ever
down on Earth...
あんたらも
地球(オカ)に降りることがあったら…
（チャイム）
She's here!
（タナベ）来た！
（ハチマキ）んっ 何だ？
What're you doing?
Sasha-san?
（タナベ）サーシャさん？
I'm scared of
seeing her again...
（サーシャ）
怖いんだ 顔を合わせるのが
I can understand! It's been
five whole years!
（タナベ）
分かります ５年ぶりですもんね
I'm sorry, could you
get the door for me?
（サーシャ）すまない
開けてやってくれないか？
Sure.
（タナベ）はい
（サーシャ）すまないな ほんとに
I'm really sorry.
（タナベ）どうぞ
Please, come in.
あっ…
エーデルさん！？
Edel-san?
What are you...
どうして…
よう エーデル
なんか雰囲気 変わったな
Hey, Edel. You seem different somehow.
（ハチマキ）えっ！？
You mean Edel-san is the old girlfriend
that you were telling us about?!
（タナベ）サーシャさんの恋人って
エーデルさんだったんですか？
（クレア）ハァ…
Hey, aren't those guys
with the OSA?
（男性１）おい あいつら
軌道保安庁じゃないか？
Oh, hell!
（男性２）マズい
（男性１）くそ
Crap!
Come along quietly!
（隊員）抵抗はやめろ！
（男性２）うるさい！ お前 来い！
Screw you!
You! Come with us!
（ハキム）ううーっ
（クレア）
うっ ああっ うっ うう…
（隊員）
銃を持ってるぞ！
（銃声）
（ハキム）うっ
（男性２）ぐおっ…
ああ…
Are you all right?
大丈夫ですか？
はっ… ハキム･アシュミード
Hakim Ashmead?
（ハキム）よく会いますね
We keep running
into each other.
（隊員）隊長 ご無事ですか？
Commander,
are you okay?
Yeah. How's it look over at the hotel?
（ハキム）
ああ ホテルのほうはどうだ？
That man named Sasha should still be there.
まだ サーシャという男が
残っているはずだが
（隊員）
それが 25号室には誰もいないと
They said that no one
was in room 25.
うん？
What an amazing coincidence!
（タナベ）すっごい偶然ですよね
Admittedly, there aren't a lot
of people on Seven...
そりゃ セブンは
人 少ないですけど
ちょっと黙ってて
Be quiet for a minute.
What did you come here for, Sasha?
何しに来たの？ サーシャ
I came to see you.
君に会いに来たのさ
Sasha-san here has his own restaurant now.
He said he worked himself to death for you.
サーシャさん
お店 持ったんですよ
エーデルさんのために
必死で頑張ったって
It's small, but the
food is...
小さいけど 味は抜群の…
- You're still using that "cook on the outskirts of town" con?
また 場末のコックネタ？
（タナベ）えっ？
エーデル 少しは笑ってくれよ
How about a little smile for me, Edel?
It's been five years, so don't be so cold.
５年ぶりだってのに つれねえなあ
It hasn't been five years.
It's been four years, eight months.
（エーデル）５年じゃないわ
４年と８か月ぶりよ
ああ？
I've been counting the days. Counting them off
until I've been away from you for five years.
ずっと数えてた
あんたと別れて ５年がたつのをね
Edel-san?
エーデルさん？
５年間 別居が続けば
相手の同意なしで離婚できる
If I stay separated from you
for five years,
...I can get a divorce with
or without your consent.
（エーデル）えっ？
（ハチマキ）どういうことだよ
What are you
talking about?
This slime used to be
my husband.
（エーデル）
こいつは私の夫だった男よ
（ハチマキ）夫！？
（タナベ）でも―
Husband?!
But he said that he proposed,
but your parents were against it.
プロポーズしたけど
ご両親に反対されたって
変わってないのね
You never change, do you?
Always making up lies on the spot...
その場限りのうそ
お涙頂戴の三文芝居
Cheap sob stories
to milk people for sympathy!
Don't be that way, baby...
I came all
the way here, so come back to...
そう言うなよ
わざわざ こんな所まで来たんだ
また俺と一緒に…
（エーデル）
また 私にだけ働かせて
遊んで暮らしたいってこと？
You want to force me to work
while you screw around, is that it?
（タナベ）あっ あの…
Um...
I was always picked
by the worst johns...
（エーデル）
ひどい客ばかり取らされたわ
They used handcuffs and collars! Electric shocks!
手錠に首輪 電気ショック
They made me get piercings
all over!
体中にピアスまでされて！
ピアスって…
Piercings?
And if I refused,
they beat me!
私が拒むと暴力を振るった
You call yourself
a husband?!
何が夫よ
"'Til death do us part"? "I love you"?
“死ぬまで一緒 愛してるよ”
They're just empty words,
you good for nothing pimp!
薄っぺらな言葉だけで
口先だけの このヒモが！
わっ エーデル
Edel!
ワイヤアンカーの射出機よ
This is a wire anchor launcher.
They use these to fire ropes into ship hulls.
宇宙船の外板に
ロープをぶち込むやつ
H-Hey, now, if you use
that on a person...
（サーシャ）お… おい
そんなもん 人に使ったら
（エーデル）死ぬわね
They'll die.
C'mon, cut it out, Edel. Okay?
なあ よせよ エーデル なあ
親もない 金もない 学もない
We've got no parents,
no money, and no education.
For people like us, that was the
only way we could survive.
そんな俺たちが生きてくためには
しかたなかったんだよ
あんたって 少しも変わらない
You haven't changed
one bit.
You keep making excuses so
you won't even have to try.
いつも そうやって
努力しないための言い訳ばかり
ぐっ…
As for me, I have a job.
（エーデル）私 働いてるの
ええっ？
Every morning, I go to the office, sit at my desk,
do my job, and go home at night.
毎朝 会社に行って
机に座って仕事して 夕方には帰る
学校のお金を稼ぐために
空いた時間にバイトも入れて
I even work part-time jobs in my free time
to earn money for school.
何だ？ そりゃ お前らしくもない
That doesn't sound like
the Edel I know.
私 バカだったけど
でも 一生懸命 勉強してるの
I used to be a fool,
but I'm studying hard.
今は派遣だけど
絶対 必ず正社員になってみせる
I'm just a temp staffer now,
...but I'm
going to be a full employee one day!
分かった
分かったから そいつを下ろせ
- All right.
I understand. Just put that thing down...
I love you, baby...
俺は お前を愛してるんだ
You've got to
be kidding me.
ふざけるな
I'll make you go away.
And you won't come back.
もう消えちまえ 私の汚点
（サーシャ）ううっ…
Tanabe!
タナベ！
どいて
（タナベ）嫌です！
Move!
I won't!
A man like him
isn't worth saving!
そんな男 救う価値はない！
この人を助けたいんじゃありません
He isn't the one that I want to save.
I don't want you to shoot him!
エーデルさんに
撃たせたくないんです！
（エーデル）はっ
We need you
at the office!
（タナベ）エーデルさんは
すごく役に立ってます
You're more useful than the Chief or Lavie-san, and way more useful than someone like me!
課長よりも ラビィさんよりも
私なんかよりも ずっと
（サーシャ）んん…
（タナベ）こんな人のために
Don't throw it all away
because of him!
（サーシャ）ううっ
（エーデル･タナベ）うっ
（エーデル）ううっ…
（サーシャ）ヘヘッ
（エーデル）サーシャ！
Sasha!
たく… 女がおごりやがって
You stupid bitch!
Think you're better than me, huh?
があああっ
（サーシャ）うわっ
ああっ…
（ハチマキ）ううっ…
Let go! Get off of me!
（サーシャ）放せ 放しやがれ！
- Like hell I will!
（ハチマキ）うるせえ！ この…
ああ… ああっ こら！
Get back here!
Move it!
（サーシャ）どけ！
（タナベ）あっ！
（ハチマキ）待て！
（サーシャ）うわっ うっ
Hold it!
（ハチマキ）待て！
（サーシャ）うわっ うっ
（殴る音）
ああっ？
（サーシャ）うおっ うっ…
I'm with the Orbital Security Agency.
軌道保安庁だ
You will be treated in
accordance with INTO law.
以後の処置は
連合法にのっとって行われる
You have the right to
contact an attorney.
お前には
弁護士と連絡を取る権利―
You have the right
to remain silent.
黙秘する権利が認められている
You're a real go-getter,
aren't you, Hakim?
仕事熱心だな ハキム
I am. Which is why I'm going to get
statements from all of you later.
ああ だから あとで―
君たちにも
事情聴取をさせてもらうよ
はいはい これで２回目か
Fine, fine... I guess
this is twice now.
You and I must have some
kind of connection, Hoshino.
（ハキム）
よくよく縁があるようだな 星野
Looks that way.
（ハチマキ）らしいな
Edel!
（サーシャ）エーデル
てめえ チクりやがったな
You ratted me out! Didn't you, you bitch?!
愛してるって言ったのによ
You said you loved me!
Were our marriage vows
nothing but lies?!
あの誓いの言葉は
うそだったのかよ
What else are you good for
besides selling your body?!
女を売る以外
てめえに何ができるんだよ！
Come on, get moving!
（隊員）とっとと来るんだ
Please, Edel! Help me! Edel!
（サーシャ）
エーデル なあ エーデル
助けてくれ エーデル！
（ドアの閉まる音）
Edel-san...
エーデルさん
（エーデル）撃つ気はなかった
I wasn't going
to shoot him.
I just wanted to make sure he'd never
come near me again, that's all.
二度と私の前に
姿を現せないようにしたかっただけ
私は…
Because I...
I'm never going back to that cesspool
of a town. Or back to that scum.
私は
ゴミためみたいな あの街には…
あんなクズのところには
二度と戻らないから
They say that Old Man Gigalt
has stabilized.
おやじさん 落ち着いたようです
That's good.
そうか
（アナウンス）
レギュラーシフトの皆さん―
Members of the regular shift,
good morning.
おはようございます
It is now 9AM, Greenwich Mean Time.
Technora is now open for business.
Good morning.
（エーデル）おはようございます
Oh, good morning. You're sure here early.
（タナベ）
あっ おはようございます
早いですね
エーデルさん 昨日は…
Edel-san, about yesterday...
船外作業免許の更新
締め切りは昨日ですよ
The deadline for your EVA license
renewal was yesterday.
えっ？ あっ ごめんなさい
I'm sorry!
Um... Where'd I?
えーっと… あれ？
（エーデル）こちらで作成して
提出しておきました
I filled it out and submitted it
for you.
えっ？ あっ…
I also filed your registration
for the sea cucumber.
（エーデル）ナマコの私物登録も
しておきましたから
Ah... Thank you, Edel-san.
あっ ありがとうございます
エーデルさん
（エーデル）フッ…
エーデルでいいよ
You can call me Edel.
gutto mizu wo nomihoshi
We gulp down some water
♪グッと水を飲み干し
yuuyakegumo miageru no sa
and look up at the evening clouds.
♪夕焼け雲見上げるのさ
♪今日も一日が終わって
kyou mo ichinichi ga owatte
Let's wind our way home under the roadside trees as another day ends.
♪街路樹の下を帰ろう
gairoju no shita wo kaerou
yaru koto darake de tenpatte
Even if life's so hectic that our tempers flare,
♪やることだらけで
テンパって、
♪無理をして、
つまずいても
muri wo shite tsumazuite mo
we push ourselves too hard, and we stumble,
♪何か必ず
つかんでるさ
nani ka kanarazu tsukanderu sa
I know there'll be something to grab hold of.
♪気楽にいこうぜ
kiraku ni ikou ze
Let's move on without a care in our hearts.
♪素晴らしい人生だから
subarashii jinsei dakara
It's a wonderful life.
♪自分を愛する
勇気を持とう
jibun wo aisuru yuuki wo motou
So let's have the courage to love ourselves.
♪新しいドア叩いて
atarashii doa tataite
Let's take it one step at a time,
♪ひとつひとつ
歩いてゆこう
hitotsu hitotsu aruite yukou
knocking on new doors on the way.
♪素晴らしい人生なのさ
subarashii jinsei na no sa
It's a wonderful life.
♪君も僕もすべての人も
kimi mo boku mo subete no hito mo
You and I and everyone else
♪喜びと悲しみの意味
yorokobi to kanashimi no imi
Keep on searching for the meaning
♪探しつづけて
so just on my way
sagashitsuzukete so just on my way
Of joy and sadness, so just on my way.
Next Time
Ignition
ハァ…
How did it go, Lavie-chan?
どうだった？
ラビィちゃん
（ユーリ）
フィー 事故だったんだ
Fee, it was an accident. Don't blame yourself.
自分を責めるな
うーん…
I'm no doctor, but I know something
that might do the trick.
俺は医者じゃないが
いい薬がある
Maybe he's...
（ノノ）ひょっとして
（医師）空間喪失症
It's Spatial Loss Disorder.
先輩 地球に戻ったほうが
いいんじゃないですか？
Senpai... Maybe it would be better
if you went back to Earth.
（ハチマキ）あっ…